It's common for researchers to normalize alpha factors
研究员经常会标准化 alpha 因子
by subtracting the mean and dividing by the standard deviation.
即减去均值并除以标准差
We can also refer to this process as Z-scoring because the result is a Z-score.
这个流程也称为 z 分数化 因为结果就是 z 分数
Z-scoring helps to standardize the data,
Z 分数化有助于标准化数据
so that it has a consistent range and distribution.
使数据保持一致的范围和分布
This makes it easier to compare and combine more than one alpha factor.
便于比较和组合多个 alpha 因子
For instance, if we assume a somewhat Gaussian distribution,
例如 假设分布是高斯分布
then about 95 percent of the values in
那么 z 分数化分布中
a Z-scored distribution would be roughly between negative two and positive two.
约 95% 的值在 -2 到 2 之间
Notice that a ranking also has
注意 排名也可以
a similar benefit of setting different alpha vectors on the same scale.
使不同的 alpha 向量具有相同的范围
Whatever the original raw alpha values are for
无论在排名时两支不同 alpha 向量的
two different alpha factors when we convert to ranks,
alpha 原始值是多少
if we had a universe of 100 stocks,
如果股票池有 100 支股票
then the ranking for any alpha would be the integers 1-100.
那么任何一个 alpha 值的排名都是 1-100 之间的整数
Note that Z-scoring has an additional benefit that you wouldn't get from ranking.
注意 与排名相比 z 分数化还有一个优势
Z-scoring sets alpha vectors on a comparable scale
即使处理规模不一样的股票池
even when we're dealing with differently sized stock universes.
Z 分数化也会使 alpha 向量变成可比较的范围
For instance, certain alpha factors may be generated on different stock universes.
某些 alpha 向量可能是根据不同的股票池生成的
So, if we had one alpha factor calculated on a universe of
例如 如果一个 alpha 向量是根据有 100 支股票的股票池生成的
100 stocks and another alpha factor calculated on 500 stocks,
另一个 alpha 向量是用有 500 支股票的股票池生成的
the rankings for the first would range from 1-100,
第一个 alpha 向量的排名范围是 1-100
while the rankings for the second would range from 1-500.
而第二个 alpha 向量的排名范围是 1-500
Converting the ranks into a Z-score would rescale
将排名转换为 z 分数会重新调整两个 alpha 向量的范围
the two alpha vectors so that they could be comparable and more readily combined.
使它们可以相互比较并且能组合到一起
Recall that ranking still makes
注意 排名会使
our alpha vectors more robust against outliers and noisy data,
alpha 向量不受离群值和噪点数据的影响
and Z-scoring does not provide the same benefit.
Z 分数化没有这种优势
So, a valid approach would be to use ranking only
有效做法是 当你知道所有 alpha 向量
when you know that all your alpha vectors are using the same stock universe.
都基于相同的股票池时 则仅使用排名方法
It's also useful to apply ranking and then Z-scoring,
如果你认为某些 alpha 向量
if you think that some of your alpha vectors may
可能是根据其他股票池生成的
be generated on different stock universes.
那么有必要先排名 再 z 分数化
One thing to remember is that when you work in a large asset management company,
需要注意的是 当你任职于一家大型资产管理公司时
you may be one of many alpha researchers,
你可能是很多 alpha 研究员中的一名
and there may be other team members,
还有很多其他团队成员
portfolio managers, who use your alpha vectors.
投资组合经理会使用你的 alpha 向量
In this case, the portfolio managers want to
在这种情形下 投资组合经理
get standardized outputs from all the quants.
希望从所有量化分析师那获得标准化输出结果
Z-scoring is one way to achieve this.
Z 分数化可以实现这一点
Academic research often uses Z-scoring,
学术研究经常使用 z 分数
as many papers are based on the work of Fama and French,
因为很多论文都是以 Fama 和 French 的论文为基础
who designed one of the first multi-factor models.
Fama 和 French 设计了首个多因子模型
Since this paper has influenced many subsequent papers in the study of factors,
因为这篇论文影响了后来的很多因子研究论文
it's likely you'll see Z-scoring in academic papers.
所以你很有可能会在学术论文中见到 z 分数